Finding Aid for Cecil O. Creal papers, 1958-1968
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Cecil O. Creal papers 1958-1968
Creal, Cecil O., 1899-
8 oversize volumes
8.2 linear feet
851008 Aa 2
Republican mayor of Ann Arbor, Michigan. Correspondence, reports, newspaper clippings, and photographs, concerning the work of city departments and such issues as tax assessments, highway construction, the building of a new city hall, the fair housing ordinance and urban renewal.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Cecil Creal (donor no. 4817 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Cecil O. Creal was Republican mayor of Ann Arbor, Michigan from 1959 to 1965.
The collection consists of topical files and other materials relating to his tenure as mayor of Ann Arbor, Michigan, 1959-1965. Some of the scrapbooks contains clippings relating to his campaign for office (1958-1959) and to Ann Arbor government issues after he left office (1965-1968).
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Mayors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; City planning--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Discrimination in housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Municipal government--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Republican Party (Mich.); Roads--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Taxation--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Urban renewal--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Mayors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; City and town halls--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; City planning--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Creal, Cecil O., 1899-; Dwellings--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Mayors--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Municipal officials.; Residential streets--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Knight's Market (Ann Arbor, Mich.)
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Topical File 1959-1965
  - Allenel Hotel (Box 1)
  - Alumni Living, Inc. (Box 1)
  - A.M.E. Church (Box 1)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 1)
  - American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (Box 1)
  - American Municipal Association (Box 1)
  - American Red Cross (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Airport (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Area Foundation (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Board of Education (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Chamber of Commerce (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Citizens Safety and Traffic Council (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Citizens Commission on Children and Youth (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Assessor (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Attorney (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Building and Safety Department (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Clerk (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Controller (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Council (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Council (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Fire Department (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Health Department (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Historical Commission (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Human Relations Dept. (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Municipal Market Commission (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Parking System (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Parks and Recreation Department (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Planning Commission (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Police Department (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Public Works Department (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Traffic and Safety Department (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Treasurer (Box 2)
  - Ann Arbor City Utilities Department (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Civic Theatre (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Junior Chamber of Commerce (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Phoenix Project Committee (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Youth Council (Box 3)
  - Ann Arbor Youth in Government Day (Box 3)
  - Annexation (Box 3)
  - Annual Awards Banquet for City Employees (Box 3)
  - Annual Reports of the City (Box 3)
  - Appointments to Boards and Commissions (Box 3)
  - Argus Cameras, Inc. (Box 3)
  - Bell Tower Inn (Box 3)
  - Bids for City Projects and Supplies (Box 3)
  - Board of Insurance Administration (Box 3)
  - Board of Review for Tax Assessments (Box 3)
  - Board of Supervisors (Washtenaw County) (Box 3)
  - Board of Trustees of the Employees Retirement System (Box 3)
  - Bonding Issues (Box 3)
  - Botanical Gardens Zoning (Box 3)
  - Budget (Box 3)
  - Bus Committee (Box 3)
  - Bus Service (Box 3)
  - Carport-Apartment Proposal (St. Joseph's Hospital) (Box 3)
  - Census 1960 (Box 3)
  - Central Business District Parking Study Committee (Box 3)
  - Charter of the City (Box 3)
  - Christmas Letters (Box 3)
  - Citizens Advisory Board on Off Street Parking (Box 3)
  - Citizens Advisory Committee on Natural Resources (Box 3)
  - Citizens for Michigan (Box 3)
  - City Employees News (Box 4)
  - City Hall Bond Issue (Box 4)
  - City Hall Committee (Box 4)
  - City Hall Construction (Box 4)
  - City Hall Dedication (Box 4)
  - City Hall Site (Box 4)
  - City Hall--United Fund (Box 4)
  - City Improvements (Box 4)
  - City Reports (All Departments) (Box 4)
  - City-Township Relations Committee (Box 4)
  - Civil Defense (Box 4)
  - Civil War Centennial Commission (Box 4)
  - Class Reunion (Class of 1924-University of Michigan) (Box 4)
  - Committee on Art and Design (Box 4)
  - Committee on Municipal Government of the Ann Arbor Citizens Council (Box 4)
  - Community College Proposals (Box 4)
  - Complaints (Box 4)
  - Conductron Corporation (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Convention (Box 4)
  - Council of Churches (Box 4)
  - County Public Works Department Committee (Box 4)
  - Dean (Elizabeth) Estate (Box 4)
  - Department Accomplishments (Box 4)
  - Detroit Edison Property (Box 4)
  - Dramatic Arts Center (Professional Theatre Proposal) (Box 4)
  - Eastbelt Bypass (U.S. 23) (Box 4)
  - Economic Development and Manpower Commission (Box 4)
  - Economic Development Committee (Chamber of Commerce) (Box 4)
  - Ernst, Louis (Box 4)
  - Fair Housing Ordinance (Box 4)
  - Fair Housing Ordinance (cont.) (Box 5)
  - Finances (Box 5)
  - Gasoline Price Probe (Box 5)
  - Hammett (Ralph) Associates (Box 5)
  - Huron Parkway (Box 5)
  - Huron River Watershed Intergovernmental Committee (Box 5)
  - Interim Committee on Aging (Box 5)
  - Inventory of City Equipment (Box 5)
  - Jacobs Plan on Job Classifications and Pay Grades (Box 5)
  - Lakewood Subdivision (Box 5)
  - League of Women Voters (Box 5)
  - Leaird Drive Improvements (Box 5)
  - Legislative-State of Michigan (Box 5)
  - Liquor Committee (Box 5)
  - Lurie Terrace Low-Income Rent Subsidy Project (Box 5)
  - March of Dimes (Box 5)
  - Mayor Creal-Civic Functions (Box 5)
  - Mayor Creal-Congratulatory Messages (Box 5)
  - Mayor Creal-Personal (Box 5)
  - Mayor's Prayer Breakfast (Box 5)
  - Mayors - 1960 Conference (Box 5)
  - Memorial Day (Box 5)
  - Metropolitan Community Research Corporation of Southeastern Michigan (Box 5)
  - Michigan Conference of Mayors (Box 5)
  - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company (Box 5)
  - Michigan Manufacturers Association (Box 5)
  - Michigan Municipal League (Box 5)
  - Michigan Municipal League (Box 6)
  - Michigan Municipal Officials Conference in Washington, D.C. (Box 6)
  - Michigan Rehabilitation Association (Box 6)
  - Michigan Week (Mayors Exchange) (Box 6)
  - Michigan Welfare League (Box 6)
  - Miller, Canfield, Paddock and Stone (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Bulletins (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Letters (Box 6)
  - Mount Hope Flag Shrine (Box 6)
  - National Guard (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 6)
  - New York Central Railroad (Box 6)
  - Northbelt By-Pass (M 14) (Box 6)
  - Northwest Park Construction Company (Shopping Center) (Box 6)
  - Ordinances (Box 6)
  - Pakistan (Proclamation, etc.) (Box 6)
  - Park Land Acquisition Study Committee (Box 6)
  - Patriotism (National Flag Week, etc.) (Box 6)
  - Personnel Records (Box 6)
  - Project 74 (Juvenile Division of the Probate Court) (Box 6)
  - Project Hope (Box 6)
  - Research Park (Box 6)
  - Reserve Units (Welcome Home, 1962) (Box 6)
  - Retaining the Character of Ann Arbor Committee (Box 6)
  - Safety Committee (Box 7)
  - Senior Citizens Guild (Box 7)
  - State of Michigan (Box 7)
  - State Street Association (Box 7)
  - Sky Walks (Box 7)
  - Tax Study (Income Tax Proposals) (Box 7)
  - Taxicab Board (Box 7)
  - Traffic Committee (Box 7)
  - Unemployment Committee (Mayor's Advisory Committee) (Box 7)
  - United Fund (Box 7)
  - United Nations Day (Box 7)
  - United States Conference of Mayors (Box 7)
  - United States Post Office (Box 7)
  - University of Michigan (Box 7)
  - Urban Renewal (Box 7)
  - Ward Boundaries Committee (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Extension Service (Box 7)
  - Washtenaw County Metropolitan Planning Commission (Box 7)
  - Welcome Wagon (Box 7)
  - Welfare Cases (Box 7)
  - Y.M.-Y.W.C.A. (Box 7)
- Other materials
  - Notebook on the Southeastern Michigan Metropolitan Community Research Corporation (Box 8)
  - Scrapbook concerning city government 1959 (Box 8)
  - Political File (Box 8)
  - Personal Correspondence (Box 8)
  - Miscellanea (Box 8)
  - Miscellanea (Box 9)
- Photographs
  - Ann Arbor. Business and public areas (Box 9)
  - Ann Arbor. City Hall. Cornerstone removal and replacement (Box 9)
  - Ann Arbor. Housing (Box 9)
  - Ann Arbor. Residential areas (Box 9)
  - Construction (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9)
- Scrapbooks
  - Pre-mayoralty scrapbook 1958-1959 (Volume 1)
  - The Life and Times of Cecil O. Creal
    - 1959 (Volume 2)
    - 1960 (Volume 3)
    - 1961 (Volume 4)
    - 1962 (Volume 5)
    - 1963 (Volume 6)
    - 1964-1968, 1964-1965 (Volume 7)
  - A Decade in the Life and Times of Cecil O. Creal 1958-1968 (Volume 8)